When we talk about what makes somebody male or female,
it sounds like it's very simple, you're either male or female,
but when you are figuring out what sex somebody is,
you're looking at internal genitalia, external genitalia,
chromosomes, certain genetic mutations, hormones,
there's just a bunch of different things.
And most people, those all line up, and some people, they don't line up.
And you might have most of the characteristics of male,
but some things that are female.
For example, one of them is called congenital androgen insensitivity.
You have a person who is XY.
Every cell in their body is XY.
But the androgen receptor, the protein that detects the testosterone, doesn't work.
So this is a person, every cell in their body is XY.
They have male levels of testosterone.
They look completely female.
These people don't get diagnosed until puberty when they don't have a period.
Because they have internal testes.
They don't have any ovaries.
They don't develop a uterus or a vagina.
You know?
Thank you.